Forever hold your piece.
American Wedding is a comedy, romance film directed by Jesse Dylan.
With high school a distant memory, Jim and Michelle are getting married — and in a hurry, since Jim's grandmother is
sick and wants to see him walk down the aisle — prompting Stifler to throw the ultimate bachelor party.
And Jim's dad is reliable as ever, doling out advice no one wants to hear.
Jim Levenstein, played by Jason Biggs.
Steve Stifler, played by Seann William Scott.
Michelle Flaherty, played by Alyson Hannigan.
Paul Finch, played by Eddie Kaye Thomas.
Kevin Myers, played by Thomas Ian Nicholas.
Cadence Flaherty, played by January Jones.
American Wedding (known as American Pie 3: The Wedding or American Pie: The Wedding, in some countries)
is a 2003 American sex comedy film written by Adam Herz and directed by Jesse Dylan.
It is the sequel to American Pie (1999) and American Pie 2
(2001), and the third of the American Pie franchise.
The film's main plot focuses on the wedding ceremony of Jim Levenstein (Jason Biggs) and Michelle Flaherty (Alyson Hannigan), while its subplot centers on Steve Stifler (Seann William Scott), and his outrageous antics
including his attempt to organize a bachelor party, teaching Jim to dance for the wedding, and competing with Finch (Eddie Kaye Thomas) to win the heart of Michelle's sister, Cadence (January Jones).
It is the last film in the series to be written by Herz, who conceptualized the franchise, and also the only theatrical film in the series in which Chris
Klein (Oz), Chris Owen (Sherman), Mena Suvari (Heather), Tara Reid (Vicky), Shannon Elizabeth (Nadia) and Natasha Lyonne (Jessica) do not appear.
Released on August 1, 2003 by Universal Pictures, American Wedding is the lowest-grossing installment in the theatrical American Pie
film series, although it was still a box office success, grossing $232.7 million worldwide on a $55 million budget.
Like the previous two films, American Wedding received mixed reviews from critics, who were
again divided on its humor but praised the cast's performances, especially Scott's.
The franchise was later expanded into a series of direct-to-DVD standalone spin-offs, under the
umbrella title American Pie Presents, that began with the release of Band Camp (2005).
A direct sequel to Wedding, titled American Reunion, was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of marriage proposal, sibling
relationship, wedding reception, handcuffs, spanner.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.